<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Material Design</string>

    <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <!-- Toolbar titles -->
    <string name="toolbar_title_home">Home</string>
    <string name="toolbar_title_explore">Explore</string>
    <string name="other_activity">Other Activity</string>

    <!-- Toolbar titles -->
    <string-array name="weekdays_list">
        <item>"Any"</item>
        <item>"Monday"</item>
        <item>"Tuesday"</item>
        <item>"Wednesday"</item>
        <item>"Thursday"</item>
        <item>"Friday"</item>
        <item>"Saturday"</item>
        <item>"Sunday"</item>
    </string-array>

    <!-- Navigation Drawer -->
    <string name="nav_drawer_item_home">Home</string>
    <string name="nav_drawer_item_explore">Explore</string>
    <string name="nav_drawer_help_and_feedback"><![CDATA[Help & feedback]]></string>
    <string name="nav_drawer_about">About</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_opened">The navigation drawer is opened</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_closed">The navigation drawer is closed</string>
    <string name="tag_nav_drawer_main_entry">nav_drawer_main_entry</string>
    <string name="tag_nav_drawer_special_entry">nav_drawer_special_entry</string>
    <string name="tools_text_account_information_username">Username</string>
    <string name="tools_text_account_information_email">user@mail.com</string>

    <!-- Typeface names -->
    <string name="typeface_roboto_regular">Roboto-Regular</string>
    <string name="typeface_roboto_medium">Roboto-Medium</string>
    <string name="title_activity_profile">ProfileActivity</string>
    <string name="large_text">
        "Material is the metaphor.\n\n"

        "A material metaphor is the unifying theory of a rationalized space and a system of motion."
        "The material is grounded in tactile reality, inspired by the study of paper and ink, yet "
        "technologically advanced and open to imagination and magic.\n"
        "Surfaces and edges of the material provide visual cues that are grounded in reality. The "
        "use of familiar tactile attributes helps users quickly understand affordances. Yet the "
        "flexibility of the material creates new affordances that supercede those in the physical "
        "world, without breaking the rules of physics.\n"
        "The fundamentals of light, surface, and movement are key to conveying how objects move, "
        "interact, and exist in space and in relation to each other. Realistic lighting shows "
        "seams, divides space, and indicates moving parts.\n\n"

        "Components with responsive elevations may encounter other components as they move between "
        "their resting elevations and dynamic elevation offsets. Because material cannot pass "
        "through other material, components avoid interfering with one another any number of ways, "
        "whether on a per component basis or using the entire app layout.\n"
        "On a component level, components can move or be removed before they cause interference. "
        "For example, a floating action button (FAB) can disappear or move off screen before a "
        "user picks up a card, or it can move if a snackbar appears.\n"
        "On the layout level, design your app layout to minimize opportunities for interference. "
        "For example, position the FAB to one side of stream of a cards so the FAB won’t interfere "
        "when a user tries to pick up one of cards.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="title_activity_excercise">ExcerciseActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_login">Sign in</string>

    <!-- Strings related to login -->
    <string name="prompt_email">Email</string>
    <string name="prompt_password">Password (optional)</string>
    <string name="action_sign_in">Sign in or register</string>
    <string name="action_sign_in_short">Sign in</string>
    <string name="error_invalid_email">This email address is invalid</string>
    <string name="error_invalid_password">This password is too short</string>
    <string name="error_incorrect_password">This password is incorrect</string>
    <string name="error_field_required">This field is required</string>
    <string name="permission_rationale">"Contacts permissions are needed for providing email
        completions."
    </string>
    <string name="title_activity_add_workout">AddWorkoutActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_category_ex">CategoryExActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_excercise_list">ExcerciseListActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main2">Main2Activity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_ex_list">ExListActivity</string>

    <!-- Chest -->
    <string name="barbell_bench_press">
        "Instructions:\n\n"
        "1. Lie back on a flat bench. Using a medium width grip, lift the bar from the rack and hold "
        "it straight over you with your arms locked. This will be your starting position.\n\n"
        "2. From the starting position, breathe in and begin coming down slowly until the bar "
        "touches your middle chest.\n\n"
        "3. After a brief pause, push the bar back to the starting position as you breathe out. Focus "
        "on pushing the bar using your chest muscles. Lock your arms and squeeze your chest in the "
        "contracted position at the top of the motion, hold for a second and then start coming down "
        "slowly again. Tip: Ideally, lowering the weight should take about twice as long as raising it.\n\n"
        "4.Repeat the movement for the prescribed amount of repetitions.\n\n"
        "5. When you are done, place the bar back in the rack.\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="dumbbell_flyes">
        "Instructions:\n\n"
        "1. Lie down on a flat bench with a dumbbell on each hand resting on top of your thighs. "
        "The palms of your hand will be facing each other.\n\n"
        "2. Then using your thighs to help raise the dumbbells, lift the dumbbells one at a time "
        "so you can hold them in front of you at shoulder width with the palms of your hands "
        "facing each other. Raise the dumbbells up like you're pressing them but stop and hold "
        "just before you lock out. This will be your starting position.\n\n"
        "3. With a slight bend on your elbows to prevent stress at the biceps tendon, lower your "
        "arms out at both sides in a wide arc until you feel a stretch on your chest. Breathe in "
        "as you perform this portion of the movement. Tip: Keep in mind that throughout the "
        "movement, the arms should remain stationary; the movement should only occur at the "
        "shoulder joint.\n\n"
        "4.	Return your arms back to the starting position as you squeeze your chest muscles and "
        "breathe out. Tip: Make sure to use the same arc of motion used to lower the weights.\n\n"
        "5. Hold for a second at the contracted position and repeat the movement for the prescribed "
        "amount of repetitions.\n\n"
    </string>

    <!-- Back -->
    <string name="wide_grip_lat_pulldown">
        "Instructions:\n\n"
        "1. Sit down on a pull-down machine with a wide bar attached to the top pulley. Make "
        "sure that you adjust the knee pad of the machine to fit your height. These pads will "
        "prevent your body from being raised by the resistance attached to the bar.\n\n"
        "2. Grab the bar with the palms facing forward using the prescribed grip. Note on grips: "
        "For a wide grip, your hands need to be spaced out at a distance wider than shoulder width. "
        "For a medium grip, your hands need to be spaced out at a distance equal to your shoulder "
        "width and for a close grip at a distance smaller than your shoulder width.\n\n"
        "3. As you have both arms extended in front of you holding the bar at the chosen grip "
        "width, bring your torso back around 30 degrees or so while creating a curvature on your "
        "lower back and sticking your chest out. This is your starting position.\n\n"
        "4.	As you breathe out, bring the bar down until it touches your upper chest by drawing the "
        "shoulders and the upper arms down and back. Tip: Concentrate on squeezing the back muscles "
        "once you reach the full contracted position. The upper torso should remain stationary and "
        "only the arms should move. The forearms should do no other work except for holding the bar; "
        "therefore, do not try to pull down the bar using the forearms.\n\n"
        "5. After a second at the contracted position squeezing your shoulder blades together, "
        "slowly raise the bar back to the starting position when your arms are fully extended and "
        "the lats are fully stretched. Inhale during this portion of the movement.\n\n"
        "6. Repeat this motion for the prescribed amount of repetitions.\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="elevated_cable_rows">
        "Instructions:\n\n"
        "1. Place it on the seat of the cable row machine.\n\n"
        "2. Sit down on the machine and place your feet on the front platform or crossbar "
        "provided making sure that your knees are slightly bent and not locked.\n\n"
        "3. Lean over as you keep the natural alignment of your back and grab the V-bar handles.\n\n"
        "4. With your arms extended pull back until your torso is at a 90-degree angle from "
        "your legs. Your back should be slightly arched, and your chest should be sticking out. You "
        "should be feeling a nice stretch on your lats as you hold the bar in front of you. This is "
        "the starting position of the exercise.\n\n"
        "5. Keeping the torso stationary, pull the handles back towards your torso while keeping "
        "the arms close to it until you touch the abdominals. Breathe out as you perform that "
        "movement. At that point you should be squeezing your back muscles hard. Hold that contraction "
        "for a second and slowly go back to the original position while breathing in.\n\n"
        "6. Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.\n\n"
    </string>

    <!-- Arms -->
    <string name="dips">
        "Instructions:\n\n"
        "1. To get into the starting position, hold your body at arm's length with your arms nearly "
        "locked above the bars.\n\n"
        "2. Now, inhale and slowly lower yourself downward. Your torso should remain upright and "
        "your elbows should stay close to your body. This helps to better focus on tricep involvement. "
        "Lower yourself until there is a 90-degree angle formed between the upper arm and forearm.\n\n"
        "3. Then, exhale and push your torso back up using your triceps to bring your body back to "
        "the starting position.\n\n"
        "4. Repeat the movement for the prescribed amount of repetitions.\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="triceps_pushdown">
        "Instructions:\n\n"
        "1. Attach a straight or angled bar to a high pulley and grab with an overhand grip "
        "(palms facing down) at shoulder width.\n\n"
        "2. Standing upright with the torso straight and a very small inclination forward, bring "
        "the upper arms close to your body and perpendicular to the floor. The forearms should be "
        "pointing up towards the pulley as they hold the bar. This is your starting position.\n\n"
        "3. Using the triceps, bring the bar down until it touches the front of your thighs and the "
        "arms are fully extended perpendicular to the floor. The upper arms should always remain "
        "stationary next to your torso and only the forearms should move. Exhale as you perform this "
        "movement.\n\n"
        "4. After a second hold at the contracted position, bring the bar slowly up to the starting "
        "point. Breathe in as you perform this step.\n\n"
        "5. Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="barbell_curl">
        "Instructions:\n\n"
        "1. Stand up with your torso upright while holding a barbell at a shoulder-width grip. "
        "The palm of your hands should be facing forward, and the elbows should be close to the torso. "
        "This will be your starting position\n\n"
        "2. While holding the upper arms stationary, curl the weights forward while contracting "
        "the biceps as you breathe out. Tip: Only the forearms should move.\n\n"
        "3. Continue the movement until your biceps are fully contracted and the bar is at shoulder "
        "level. Hold the contracted position for a second and squeeze the biceps hard.\n\n"
        "4. Slowly begin to bring the bar back to starting position as your breathe in.\n\n"
        "5. Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="dumbbell_bicep_curl">
        "Instructions:\n\n"
        "1. Stand up straight with a dumbbell in each hand at arm's length. Keep your elbows close "
        "to your torso and rotate the palms of your hands until they are facing forward. This will "
        "be your starting position.\n\n"
        "2. Now, keeping the upper arms stationary, exhale and curl the weights while contracting "
        "your biceps. Continue to raise the weights until your biceps are fully contracted and the "
        "dumbbells are at shoulder level. Hold the contracted position for a brief pause as you "
        "squeeze your biceps.\n\n"
        "3. Then, inhale and slowly begin to lower the dumbbells back to the starting position.\n\n"
        "4. Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.\n\n"
    </string>

    <!-- Shoulder -->
    <string name="seated_barbell_press">
        "Instructions:\n\n"
        "1. Sit on a Military Press Bench with a bar behind your head and either have a spotter "
        "give you the bar (better on the rotator cuff this way) or pick it up yourself carefully "
        "with a pronated grip (palms facing forward). Tip: Your grip should be wider than shoulder "
        "width and it should create a 90-degree angle between the forearm and the upper arm as the "
        "barbell goes down.\n\n"
        "2. Once you pick up the barbell with the correct grip length, lift the bar up over your "
        "head by locking your arms. Hold at about shoulder level and slightly in front of your head. "
        "This is your starting position.\n\n"
        "3. Lower the bar down to the collarbone slowly as you inhale.\n\n"
        "4. Lift the bar back up to the starting position as you exhale.\n\n"
        "5. Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="power_partials">
        "Instructions:\n\n"
        "1. Stand up with your torso upright and a dumbbell on each hand being held at arm’s length. "
        "The elbows should be close to the torso.\n\n"
        "2. The palms of the hands should be facing your torso. Your feet should be about shoulder "
        "width apart. This will be your starting position.\n\n"
        "3. Keeping your arms straight and the torso stationary, lift the weights out to your sides "
        "until they are about shoulder level height while exhaling.\n\n"
        "4. Feel the contraction for a second and begin to lower the weights back down to the starting "
        "position while inhaling. Tip: Keep the palms facing down with the little finger slightly higher "
        "while lifting and lowering the weights as it will concentrate the stress on your shoulders"
        "mainly.\n\n"
        "5. Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.\n\n"
    </string>

    <!-- Abs -->
    <string name="decline_crunch">
        "Instructions:\n\n"
        "1. Secure your legs at the end of the decline bench and lie down.\n\n"
        "2. Now place your hands lightly on either side of your head keeping your elbows in. Tip: "
        "Don't lock your fingers behind your head.\n\n"
        "3. While pushing the small of your back down in the bench to better isolate your abdominal "
        "muscles, begin to roll your shoulders off it.\n\n"
        "4. Continue to push down as hard as you can with your lower back as you contract your "
        "abdominals and exhale. Your shoulders should come up off the bench only about four inches, "
        "and your lower back should remain on the bench. At the top of the movement, contract your "
        "abdominals hard and keep the contraction for a second. Tip: Focus on slow, controlled "
        "movement - don't cheat yourself by using momentum.\n\n"
        "5. After the one second contraction, begin to come down slowly again to the starting "
        "position as you inhale.\n\n"
        "6. Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="leg_raise_parrallel_bars">
        "Instructions:\n\n"
        "1. Position your body on the vertical leg raise bench so that your forearms are resting "
        "on the pads next to the torso and holding on to the handles. Your arms will be bent at a "
        "90-degree angle.\n\n"
        "2. The torso should be straight with the lower back pressed against the pad of the machine "
        "and the legs extended pointing towards the floor. This will be your starting position.\n\n"
        "3. Now as you breathe out, lift your legs up as you keep them extended. Continue this "
        "movement until your legs are roughly parallel to the floor and then hold the contraction for "
        "a second. Tip: Do not use any momentum or swinging as you perform this exercise.\n\n"
        "4. Slowly go back to the starting position as you breathe in.\n\n"
        "5. Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.\n\n"
    </string>

    <!-- Legs -->
    <string name="leg_press">
        "Instructions:\n\n"
        "1. Using a leg press machine, sit down on the machine and place your legs on the platform "
        "directly in front of you at a medium (shoulder width) foot stance. (Note: For the purposes "
        "of this discussion we will use the medium stance described above which targets overall "
        "development; however, you can choose any of the three stances described in the foot "
        "positioning section).\n\n"
        "2. Lower the safety bars holding the weighted platform in place and press the platform all "
        "the way up until your legs are fully extended in front of you. Tip: Make sure that you do "
        "not lock your knees. Your torso and the legs should make a perfect 90-degree angle. This "
        "will be your starting position.\n\n"
        "3. As you inhale, slowly lower the platform until your upper and lower legs make a "
        "90-degree angle.\n\n"
        "4. Pushing mainly with the heels of your feet and using the quadriceps go back to the "
        "starting position as you exhale.\n\n"
        "5. Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions and ensure to lock the safety pins "
        "properly once you are done. You do not want that platform falling on you fully loaded.\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="barbell_squat">
        "Instructions:\n\n"
        "1. This exercise is best performed inside a squat rack for safety purposes. To begin, first "
        "set the bar on a rack just above shoulder level. Once the correct height is chosen and the "
        "bar is loaded, step under the bar and place the back of your shoulders (slightly below the "
        "neck) across it.\n\n"
        "2. Hold on to the bar using both arms at each side and lift it off the rack by first "
        "pushing with your legs and at the same time straightening your torso.\n\n"
        "3. Step away from the rack and position your legs using a shoulder-width medium stance with "
        "the toes slightly pointed out. Keep your head up always and maintain a straight back. This "
        "will be your starting position.\n\n"
        "4. Begin to slowly lower the bar by bending the knees and sitting back with your hips as you "
        "maintain a straight posture with the head up. Continue down until your hamstrings are on your "
        "calves. Inhale as you perform this portion of the movement.\n\n"
        "5. Begin to raise the bar as you exhale by pushing the floor with the heel or middle of your "
        "foot as you straighten the legs and extend the hips to go back to the starting position.\n\n"
        "6. Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="title_activity_register">RegisterActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_edit_profile">EditProfileActivity</string>

</resources>
